Philia Wang

Digital Designer

With more than 5 years of experience working across the marketing & design fields. Passionate about user-centred design with focusing on not only looks & feels, but also perspectives like information architecture, design research & UI/UX. I love to create a broader picture view of the users' experience for products.

Contact

S +61 478 729 163

philia 1010@gmail.com

Portfolio

philia.wang/portfolio/

Skillset

branding

UI prototyping

wireframing

visual design

design research

interactivity & animation

Techniques

Adobe Ps/Ai/Id/Ae
Figma/Sketch/Invision
HTML/CSS

Activity

2020 speaker @Taiwanese
Designers in Australia

2017 Talk UX / Ladies UX Taipei

2017 HTML/CSS coding bootcamp @SkillTree, Taipei

Education

2020 UI/UX Design Specialization at CalArts on Coursera

2015 MS, Landscape Architecture National Taiwan University

Experience

LEAD DESIGNER

Sydney
Dec 2019 - Current

THE CHRISTMAS COMPANY

- Collaborate with the team to win impressive tenders.
- Plan, design & create project presentation for tendering.
- Maintain & update the company website using WordPress.
- Create digital marketing collaterals for Instagram & Facebook posts.
- Build brand guideline to aim for the right branding direction.
- Product research & development.
- Build a file system using categorization to make a designer-friendly environment.

MOTION GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Sydney

TIME PLANNING AND PROGRAMMING

Feb 2018 - Dec 2019

- Made animations to aid interpretation for construction tendering projects.
- Prepared print & digital materials for stakeholders.
- Liaising stakeholders ensure a consistent rendition of both the construction sequence & the site logistics methodology throughout all visual narratives.
- Collaborated with team to build massive projects for motion graphics.
- Mentor new hires to improve their professional practice with new knowledge & skills.

PROJECT MANAGEMENT SPECIALIST

Taipei

NEW TAIPEI CITY GOVERNMENT (CONTRACT)

Oct 2017 - Dec 2017

- Responsible for the planning & execution of the New Taipei City Spring Festival.
- Engaged in marketing decision & developed design strategies with stakeholders, including key visuals & peripheral products.
- Managed campaign events, participated in rundowns for press conferences & maintained good communications between all stakeholders.

GRAPHIC / EXHIBITION DESIGNER

Taipei

Taipei

UNIQUE DESIGN

Dec 2016 - Apr 2017

- Prepared print & digital collaterals for marketing campaigns.
- Developed commercial space design concepts and developed aesthetic solutions.
- Liaised with stakeholders to ensure good communication in the design process.

RESEARCHER

NATIONAL TAIWAN UNIVERSITY

Jun 2015 - Jul 2016

- Researched & analyzed environmental benefits on human psychology.
- Designed print collaterals for landscape academic seminars and events.
- Constructed a webpage for the studio utilizing Wix.